Guide to the Top Value Television papers, 1964-2004 (bulk 1971-1977) 1964-2004 PFA.MSS.008
BAMPFA Film Library
- Series 1: Productions, 1964, 1967, 1972-1979, undated; 57 Folders, 14 Binders
  - Subseries 15: Videotape raw shot logs and edit logs, 1974-1976, undated; 15 Binders
    - Tape logs for THE WORLD'S LARGEST TV STUDIO and FOUR MORE YEARS, 1972; 1 Binder (Carton 2, Binder 1)
    - GERALD FORD'S AMERICA tape logs, "Volume I: 1-100", 1974, undated; 1 Binder (Carton 2, Binder 2)
    - GERALD FORD'S AMERICA tape logs, "Volume II: 101->", 1974, undated, 1 Binder (Carton 2, Binder 3)
    - GERALD FORD'S AMERICA tape logs, "Volume III: 260 ->", 1974, undated; 1 Binder (Carton 2, Binder 4)
    - GERALD FORD'S AMERICA tape logs, "GFA Vol. 4 Orig.", 1974, undated; 1 Binder (Carton 2, Binder 5)
    - GERALD FORD'S AMERICA tape logs, "GFA 5", 1974, undated; 1 Binder (Carton 2, Binder 6)
    - TVTV GOES TO THE SUPERBOWL tape logs, "Superbowl", 1976; 1 Binder (Carton 2, Binder 7)
    - TVTV GOES TO THE SUPERBOWL tape logs, "Superbowl 1 Orig.", 1976; 1 Binder (Carton 2, Binder 8)
    - THE BOB DYLAN HARD RAIN SPECIAL tape logs, "Bob Dylan Special Duplicate", 1976; 1 Binder (Carton 2, Binder 9)
    - SUPER VISION (1976) tape logs, "Super Vision Original", 1975-1976; 1 Binder (Carton 3, Binder 10)
    - TVTV LOOKS AT THE OSCARS tape logs, "Oscars Pt. 1 Original", 1975-1976; 1 Binder (Carton 3, Binder 11)
    - TVTV LOOKS AT THE OSCARS tape logs, "Oscars Pt. 2 Originals", 1976; 1 Binder (Carton 3, Binder 12)
    - TVTV LOOKS AT THE OSCARS tape logs, "Quad Log + Edit Log", 1976; 1 Binder (Carton 3, Binder 13)
    - TVTV LOOKS AT THE OSCARS tape logs, "Edit Log Oscars", 1976; 1 Binder (Carton 3, Binder 14)
    - "Shields Log," unknown production, 1 Binder (Carton 3, Binder 15)
- Series 2: TVTV corporate papers and general correspondence, 1972-1979, 1981, undated; 9 Folders
  This series is divided into two subseries:
  Subseries 1: Corporate papers, 1973-1978, undated
  Subseries 2: General correspondence, 1972-1979, 1981
  Arranged chronologically within folders, this series consists of papers related to the incorporation, staffing, and operations of TVTV, as well as general correspondence related to the organization. These papers are primarily separate from any particular project and reflect the evolving goals of TVTV.
  - Subseries 1: Corporate papers, 1973-1978, undated; 2 Folders
    This subseries consists of documents and correspondence related to the operations of TVTV as a corporate entity. These include budget, staffing, and technical concerns, as well as creative and personal discussions.
    - Corporate papers, 1973-1976; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 58)
    - Corporate papers, 1977-1978, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 59)
  - Subseries 2: General correspondence, 1972-1979, 1981, 1983, 1986-1987, 2012, undated; 7 Folders
    This subseries has been arranged by date, as there was no original order to the TVTV correspondence files. The exceptions to this are as follows: a group of correspondence with WNET regarding distribution and broadcast of TVTV materials; a packet of materials related to the distribution of TVTV works by Electronic Arts Intermix; and correspondence with PFA curator Steve Seid about TVTV donations. These materials have been kept separate and arranged by date within folders.
    - General correspondence, 1972-1975, 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 60)
    - General correspondence, 1/1/1976-8/31/1976, 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 61)
    - General correspondence, 9/1/1976-12/31/1976, 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 62)
    - General correspondence, 1977, 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 63)
    - General Correspondence, 1978-1979, 1981, 1983, 1986-1987, 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 64)
    - WNET distribution correspondence, 1975-1976; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 65)
    - Correspondence with Steve Seid, 2012; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 66)
- Series 3: Artwork and related materials, 1972, 1974, undated; 9 Folders, 7 Containers
  This series is subdivided into four subseries:
  Subseries 1: Scrapbooks
  Subseries 2: Stickers, posters, stationery, artwork mockups, and related material
  Subseries 3: Original artwork and photographs, undated
  Subseries 4: 3-dimensional artefacts
  This series consists of original artwork, designs and mockups for stationery and promotional materials, photographs, and scrapbooks. Some of these materials are associated with TVTV productions, or were created as artistic diaries of the productions, while others were intended for general use by the group. TVTV designed many versions of its corporate letterhead, frequently designing special stationery, stamps, and other materials specifically themed around a show under production. Much of the correspondence TVTV conducted was typed on this custom-made stationery. This series contains both original drawings for these materials and copies of the finished products, as well as a collection of stationery designs from various organizations that served as inspiration. Also included in this series are similar works created by affiliated groups such as Ant Farm. Three scrapbooks in this series document daily life of the TVTV crew on location shoots. Materials for mock press badges include photographs, mockups, and printed badges.
  - Subseries 1: Scrapbooks, 1972, 1974, undated; 4 Containers
    Three scrapbooks in this subseries were made in the process of shooting footage for THE WORLD'S LARGEST TV STUDIO, FOUR MORE YEARS, and LORD OF THE UNIVERSE. The scrapbooks include photographs of the TVTV crew on location, as well as many humorous drawings, notes, newspaper clippings, and other additions. An additional scrapbook consists of similar materials, but is unrelated to a specific production.
    - Scrapbook related to THE WORLD'S LARGEST TV STUDIO, 1972; 1 Scrapbook (Container 1)
    - Scrapbook related to FOUR MORE YEARS, 1972; 1 Scrapbook (Container 2)
    - Photo album diary related to THE LORD OF THE UNIVERSE, 1974; 1 Scrapbook (Container 3)
    - Scrapbook of artwork, clippings, and sketches, 1 Scrapbook (Container 4)
  - Subseries 2: Stickers, posters, stationery, artwork mockups, and related material, 6 Folders
    - Original artwork, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 67)
    - Posters, stickers, flyers, and related material, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 68)
    - Stationery and letterhead, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 69)
    - Duplicates of stationery and letterhead, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 70)
    - Inspirational letterhead designs, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 71)
    - Ant Farm and related organizations' letterhead, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 72)
  - Subseries 3: Identification photos, press badges, and original artwork, 3 Folders
    This subseries consists of mock press badges for TVTV crew. Materials are separated by type: original mockups for the badges, printed badges, and identification photographs to be affixed to the completed badges. The photographs have been kept in their original envelopes.
    - Artwork and mockups for badges, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 73)
    - Printed press badges, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 74)
    - Identification photographs, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 75)
  - Subseries 4: Three-dimensional objects, 3 Containers
    This subseries consists of a variety of objects created by TVTV. Included is an embosser for the TVTV corporate seal; a plastic colored map of the United States; a roll of custom TVTV labels; and a set of political pins.
    - TVTV corporate seal embosser, undated; 1 Item (Container 5)
      This is a standard office embosser for paper that represents the corporate seal of TVTV, Inc. Includes an imitation leather pouch. Dimensions are approximately 4.5 in x 4.5 in. x 2 in..
    - Shrinky-dink map, undated; 1 Item (Container 6)
      Plastic "Shrinky-dink" map of the United States with the TVTV logo drawn on it. Dimensions are approximately 3 in. x 2 in..
    - TVTV tape labels, undated; 1 Item (Container 7)
      This is a roll of labels printed with blank fields for TVTV productions, probably intended for use on 1-inch Type C videotape cases. Dimensions are approximately 2 in. x 5 in.
- Series 4: Publications and writings by and about TVTV, 1972-1978, 1983-1984, 1997, 2004, undated; 13 Folders
  This series is subdivided into five subseries:
  Subseries 1: Published material by TVTV and members, 1973, 1974, 1978
  Subseries 2: Published material about TVTV, bulk 1974-1976, 1972, 1983, 2004, undated
  Subseries 3: Unpublished material about TVTV, 1976, 1997, undated
  Subseries 4: Exhibition and lecture materials, 1971, 1976, 2004, undated
  Subseries 5: TVTV distribution through Electronic Arts Intermix, 1974-1983 (bulk)
  This series is arranged chronologically by material type and consists of published and unpublished writings by and about TVTV and its members. These writings were created in diverse settings and for very different needs and include: critical and humorous print articles, announcements and advertisements for works by TVTV, scholarly and technical writings, and materials related to exhibitions featuring TVTV. Included is a booklet published by TVTV in 1974, The Prime Time Survey, which recounts the history of television, details the state of the art of video recording technology, and predicts the future of broadcast media.
  - Subseries 1: Published material by TVTV and members, 1973, 1975, 1974, 1978; 3 Folders
    - Newspaper and magazine clippings, 1973, 1975, 1978; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 76)
    - The Prime Time Survey, 1974; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 77)
    - Promotional material for and reviews of The Prime Time Survey, 1974; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 78)
  - Subseries 2: Published material about TVTV, Bulk 1974-1976, 1972, 1983, 2004, undated; 1 Folder
    This subseries consists of materials about TVTV and its members that appeared in published form. This includes critical assessments, announcements and listings of TVTV broadcasts, and retrospective pieces. These materials are arranged chronologically, with 1976 representing the most prolific year.
    - Published material about TVTV, 1972, 1974-1975, 1983, 1985, 2004, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 79)
  - Subseries 3: Unpublished material about TVTV, 1976, 1997, undated; 1 Folder
    This subseries consists of unpublished writings about TVTV, including a conference paper, a student term paper, and a draft of an apparently unpublished article.
    - Unpublished material about TVTV, 1976, 1997, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 80)
  - Subseries 4: Exhibition and lecture materials, 1971, 1976, 1981, 1984, 1986, 2004, undated; 7 Folders
    This subseries consists of materials created in preparation for lectures by TVTV members, as well as programs, correspondence, and other materials related to museum exhibitions featuring TVTV.
    - Lecture materials, 1971, 1976, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 81)
    - National Video Festival program, 1981; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 82)
    - Whitney Museum of Art exhibition, 1984; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 83)
    - International Center for Photography exhibition correspondence, 1986; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 84)
    - International Center for Photography exhibition flyers and programs, 1986; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 85)
    - Long Beach Museum of Art flyer, 1986; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 86)
    - Museum of Television and Radio festival program, 2004; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 87)
  - Subseries 5: TVTV distribution through Electronic Arts Intermix, 1974-1983 (bulk); 1 Folder
    This subseries consists of a collection of published materials about TVTV works as well as a filmography and various similar items. These were apparently sent as a packet to Electronic Arts Intermix (EAI), a video distributor in New York City, in preparation for the distribution of TVTV's works in the mid-1980s.
    - TVTV EAI distribution information, 1974-1983 (bulk); 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 88)
- Series 5: Side projects and post-TVTV materials, 1975-1979, undated; 6 Folders
  Subseries 1: TVTV and the Coalition for New Public Affairs Programming, 1975-1976, undated
  Subseries 2: Michael Shamberg: MALLORY OF EVEREST, 1977, undated
  Subseries 3: Wendy Apple and Megan Williams: DAYDREAMS, 1977, undated
  Subseries 4: Megan Williams/Videopolis: DRUG OF CHOICE, 1977-1978, undated
  Subseries 5: Michael Shamberg: THE SIDEKICK,1978-1979, undated
  This series is arranged chronologically and consists of materials produced by TVTV and its members outside of official TVTV productions. This includes materials related to an independent television advocacy group supported by TVTV members, as well as materials created by TVTV members for film and television productions outside of TVTV, during and immediately after the dissolution of the collective. The items created for outside productions include research materials, correspondence, and production notes such as budgets and treatments.
  - Subseries 1: TVTV and the Coalition for New Public Affairs Programming, 1975-1976, undated; 1 Folder
    This subseries consists primarily of correspondence related to TVTV's participation in the Coalition for New Public Affairs Programming. CNPAP was an advocacy group that aimed to direct public broadcasting funding to alternative (or alternative-minded) producers such as TVTV and similar groups.
    - TVTV and the Coalition for New Public Affairs Programming, 1975-1976, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 89)
  - Subseries 2: Michael Shamberg: MALLORY OF EVEREST, 1977, undated; 1 Folder
    - Michael Shamberg: MALLORY OF EVEREST, 1977, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 90)
  - Subseries 3: Wendy Apple and Megan Williams: DAYDREAMS, 1977, undated; 2 Folders
    - DAYDREAMS production notes, documents, and correspondence, 1977, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 91)
    - DAYDREAMS research materials, 1977, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 92)
  - Subseries 4: Megan Williams/Videopolis: DRUG OF CHOICE, 1977-1978, undated; 1 Folder
    - Megan Williams/Videopolis: DRUG OF CHOICE, 1977-1978, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 93)
  - Subseries 5: Michael Shamberg: THE SIDEKICK, 1978-1979, undated; 1 Folder
    - Michael Shamberg: THE SIDEKICK, 1978-1979, undated; 1 Folder (Carton 4, Folder 94)